Ice Cold, Hot Wired.
Gone in Sixty Seconds is a action, crime,
thriller film directed by Dominic Sena.
Upon learning that he has to come out of retirement to steal 50 cars in one night to save his brother Kip's life, former car
thief Randall "Memphis" Raines enlists help from a few "boost happy" pals to accomplish a seemingly impossible feat.
From countless car chases to relentless cops, the high-octane excitement builds as
Randall swerves around more than a few roadblocks to keep Kip alive.
Memphis Raines, played by Nicolas Cage.
Sara 'Sway' Wayland, played by Angelina Jolie.
Kip Raines, played by Giovanni Ribisi.
Otto Halliwell, played by Robert Duvall.
Det. Roland Castlebeck, played by Delroy Lindo.
Detective Drycoff, played by Timothy Olyphant.
Gone in 60 Seconds (also known as Gone in Sixty Seconds) is a 2000 American action heist film starring Nicolas Cage, Angelina
Jolie, Giovanni Ribisi, Christopher Eccleston, Robert Duvall, Vinnie Jones, Delroy Lindo, Chi McBride, and Will Patton.
The film was directed by Dominic Sena, written by Scott
Rosenberg, and produced by Jerry Bruckheimer.
The film is a loose remake of the H.
Halicki film Gone in 60 Seconds (1974).
The film was shot from May to October 1999, throughout
Los Angeles and Long Beach, California.
It was released on June 9, 2000, by Buena Vista Pictures
(through its Touchstone Pictures label).
Upon release, Gone in 60 Seconds received generally negative reviews from critics, with
criticism for its writing, direction, as well as acting and action sequences.
Despite the critical response, the film grossed $237 million
against an estimated production budget of $90 million.
The film explores themes of california, sibling
relationship, car race, brother, blackmail.
The tone is intense.